Melissa Ortíz R.

UX-UT DESTGNER

Enthusiastic multidisciplinary designer with 2+ years of architecture & design experience. My passion is creating exceptional experiences in digital products and designing intuitive, enjoyable solutions throughout the user journey.

My architecture background has given me a unique perspective as a designer. Creative thinking, user-centered design and technical skills, are the common denominators I share in both of my career paths.

A never-ending learner who enjoys solving complex problems.

Experience

April 2022 - Present

Architectural lead designer

GonSAS Company

- Successfully led multiple projects from the proposal through completion, ensuring adherence to timelines and budgets.
- Starting with user understanding and requirements, created highly balanced spaces between form and function to elevate user interaction and experience within the designed spaces.
- Led the design team into winning six proposals of high-level contracts with multiple universities in Bogota, summing up 1.5MM USD in valuation.
- Played a key role with compliance and governance documentation of a 70 MM USD solar park, showing versatility and adaptation skills.

September 2021 - March 2022

Architectural Designer

Kodama Company

- Led the design process for 50 high-profile residential eco-friendly homes, each one with multiple customizations in style, interior design and materials.
- Applied a design thinking approach to create spaces that enhanced user experience, functionality and sustainability.
- Used 3D modeling software to visualize designs in an user-friendly way for customers.
- Delivered design presentations to clients, and led meetings to get user input and feedback.
- Refined designs according to client's input, ensuring the final outcome met all requirements, budget and customer's satisfaction.

Diciembre 2019 - Mayo 2021

Intern

Urbanittá

- Developed urban design proposals, employing innovative solutions for the revitalization and utility of space.
- Analyzed social behaviors, mobility patterns and urbanistic zone distributions to find the most functional configurations for citizens.
- Presented the project design in "Alma Viva contest".

Independent Projects and Apps

January 2024

Pokemon Web - app Game

- Web-app developed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- The website features six characters and is designed with a thoughtfully selected color palette and typography to enhance user engagement

September 2023

Food Market App http://surl.li/nkfoo

- App designed using Figma, Illustrator and Photoshop.
- The application aimed to create a recipe app connected to a supermarket to ensure product delivery, cost estimation, and recipe guidance.

June 2023

QuickNotes App http://surl.li/nkfqy

- This app included all the essential note-taking features and ensuring efficiency in its usability

WANT TO KNOW MORE ABOUT ME?







+57 302 207 0763

Click here to see my portfolio

Education

2017 - 2021

Universidad de La Salle

Bachelor Degree in Architecture Design GPA: 4.3/5.0

Platzi

User Centered Design User Research Advanced Figma Design Sprint Mobile Interface Design Design Thinking

Awards and Recognitions

2021

Universidad de La Salle

Meritorious Research Award Nominee

<u> 2021</u>

Urbanittá

Finalist Alma Viva Contest

2020

ACFA

Finalist Ciudades y arquitecturas abiertas

SKILLS

Design tools

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign.

Design Methods

Wireframing, typography, interface design, User research, Design sprint, Design thinking.

Prototyping

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.